Preliminary Guide to the Carl Purington Rollins Papers
Yale University Arts Library
Carl Purington Rollins papers
1880-1983
AOB 9
Yale University Arts Library
40
(77 boxes)
The Carl Purington Rollins papers document Rollins's career as a master printer, graphic designer, author, and educator. The collection consists of personal and business correspondence; writings by Rollins and others; materials designed and/or printed by Rollins and others; and research files and notebooks.
Rollins, Carl Purington, 1880-1960
Associated Materials
The Records of the Yale University Press (RU 554), which are housed in the department of Manuscripts and Archives in Sterling Memorial Library, contain additional Rollins correspondence and documents relating to his tenure at the Press from 1918 to 1948.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Rollins family members and acquired by purchase.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Carl Purington Rollins was born in West Newbury, Massachusetts, in 1880. He attended Harvard University from 1897 to 1900, and worked for the Georgetown Advocate, a small country newspaper. He subsequently worked for the Carl Heintzemann Press in Boston before joining New Clairvaux, a rural Utopian community, in Montague, Massachusetts, in 1903. Rollins taught a printing course in the community's school and ran the New Clairvaux Press. He left the community in 1904, after losing the sight in one eye, but returned to Montague several years later, and purchased the Dyke Mill. While the New Clairvaux community failed in 1908, Rollins remained in Montague where he had established an arts and crafts cooperative at Dyke Mill where furniture, textiles, and printed works were made and sold. Eventually, the business became a press exclusively, the Montague Press. In 1918, Rollins joined the staff of the Yale University Press and was appointed Printer to the University in 1920. In the course of four decades, he designed more than two thousand books for Yale University Press as well as most of the University's ephemeral materials. Rollins taught a course in bibliography and established the Bibliographical Press in the University library for student use. He also established a private press, At the Sign of the Chorobates, from which he printed publications including Wine Making for the Amateur (1930). He was the recipient of numerous awards and prizes, including the highest award of the American Institute of Graphic Arts in 1941. He received honorary degrees from Yale and was named Printer Emeritus when he retired from the University in 1948. Rollins married Margaret Dickey in 1915, and they had two children, Elizabeth and Caroline. He died in New Haven, Connecticut, in 1960.
A bibliography, The Works of Carl P. Rollins (New Haven, CT: Yale University Library, 1982), associated with an exhibit in Sterling Memorial Library in 1982-1983, and prepared by Gay Walker, is an invaluable source of information on Rollins and his work.
References: Katherine M. Ruffin and Chika Ota contributed to this biographical statement.
Scope and Contents
The Carl Purington Rollins papers document Rollins's career as a master printer, graphic designer, author, and educator. The collection consists of personal and business correspondence; writings by Rollins and others; materials designed and/or printed by Rollins and others; and research files and notebooks. The materials document Rollins's design and printing work at the community of New Clairvaux (New Clairvaux Press), Dyke Mill (Montague Press), and the Yale Press, as well as his own hand press, At the Sign of the Chorobates.
This preliminary inventory first lists the larger group of material that was given to Yale by the Rollins family in the early 1980s, and preliminarily processed in 1998, and then lists material acquired by purchase in 2002. Oversize material is indicated by Oversize (legal size document box) and Oversize + (folio-size flat boxes). The lack of dates for some material reflects the varying levels of processing of the papers.
Rollins's library of books related to printing and printing history was given to the Arts of the Book Collection in 1981, and has been cataloged in Orbis, Yale's online catalog.
Arrangement
Preliminarily arranged in twelve series and one addition: I. Correspondence, 1902-1963. II. Writings, 1930-1983. III. Works and Projects, 1900-1963. IV. Awards, Honors, and Events, 1933-1963. V. Book Clubs and Bibliophile Groups, 1902-1965. VI. Presses, 1902-1963. VII. Printers and Designers, 1897-1976. VIII. Paper Specimens, 1877-1942. IX. Type Specimens, 1929-1949. X. Library and Museum Publications, 1910-1962. XI. Photographs and Realia, 1902-1958. XII. Notebooks, 1903-1958. 2002 Addition, 1903-1974.
Collective settlements -- Massachusetts -- Montague; Printing -- Connecticut; Printing -- Massachusetts; Utopian socialism -- Massachusetts; Letterpress printing; Type specimens (documents); Printers; Rollins, Carl Purington, 1880-1960; Dwiggins, W. A. (William Addison), 1880-1956; Rogers, Bruce, 1870-1957; At the Sign of the Chorobates; Heintzemann Press; Montague Press; New Clairvaux Press; Bibliographical Press; Yale University Press
- Correspondence, 1902-1963; Series I
  - Letters from Carl Rollins
    - Alexander, Edward, 1949 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Greer, 1948-1954 (Box 1)
    - Bauman, Mr., 1947 (Box 1)
    - Benett, Paul, 1951 (Box 1)
    - Berdan, Mrs., 1931 (Box 1)
    - Bingham, William, 1932 (Box 1)
    - Blackwell Booksellers, 1939 (Box 1)
    - Booth, 1941 (Box 1)
    - Cameron, Donald, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Cary, Melbert Jr., 1939 (Box 1)
    - Champe, Elizabeth, 1946 (Box 1)
    - Connell, R.F., 1938 (Box 1)
    - Farnum, Royal, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Farquhar, Samuel, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Ferme, Edgard, 1941 (Box 1)
    - Glick, Evelyn, 1933 (Box 1)
    - Green, Charles, 1932 (Box 1)
    - Jorgenson, Arthur (Box 1)
    - Main, Fred, 1941 (Box 1)
    - Rollins, Mrs. (Rollins's mother), 1905 (Box 1)
    - Rudge, William, 1947 (Box 1)
    - Scott, Catherine (Box 1)
    - Scripps College, Board of Admissions, 1940 (Box 1)
    - Virgin, Edward, 1902-1917, undated (Box 1)
    - War Production Board, 1943 (Box 1)
    - Washburn, Gordon (Box 1)
    - White, 1939 (Box 1)
    - Whiting, Fred, 1905-1950 (Box 1)
    - Wilberforce, Robert (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Letters to Carl Rollins
    - Adams, Donald, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Adams, Randolph, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Adelman, Howard B., 1944 (Box 2)
    - Adler, Elmor, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Aiken, John A., 1916 (Box 2)
    - Alexander, Edward P., 1949 (Box 2)
    - Allen, Greer (Box 2)
    - Alliger, Lewis, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Andrews, Charles and Evangeline, 1921 (Box 2)
    - Angelo, Valenti, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Archibald, E. Parker, 1946 (Box 2)
    - Ashbee, C. R., 1932 (Box 2)
    - Augustine, Lee, 1945, 1946 (Box 2)
    - Beilenson, Peter, undated (Box 2)
    - Benit, Bill, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Benson, Mrs. John, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Bentley, Wilder, 1932-1937 (Box 2)
    - Bolley, John R., undated (Box 2)
    - Booth, Roy H., 1941 (Box 2)
    - Bradford, Arthur H., 1943 (Box 2)
    - Brady, Rosemary, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Brinton, Jasper, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Brooke, Tucker, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Bunker, E. K., 1940 (Box 2)
    - Cameron, Donald, 1938 (Box 2)
    - Carter, J. W., 1937 (Box 2)
    - Carter, George H., 1933 (Box 2)
    - Carter, Will, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Cary, Melbert, 1940, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Chamberlain, John, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Champe, Elizabeth, 1946 (Box 2)
    - Cleeton, Glen U., 1940 (Box 2)
    - Clement, Florence, 1934 (Box 2)
    - Cole, Philip P., 1932 (Box 2)
    - Connell, R. F., 1938 (Box 2)
    - Cross, Wilbur, 1934 (Box 2)
    - Cushing, Harvey, 1936 (Box 2)
    - Decker, Blanche, 1937 (Box 2)
    - Dennett, Mary Ware, 1940 (Box 2)
    - DeRenne, Kentwyn, 1935-1940 (Box 2)
    - DeVoto, Bernard, 1937 (Box 2)
    - Donnelley, Gaylord, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Duncan, Harry, 1950 (Box 2)
    - Duschness, Philip, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Dustin, H., 1944 (Box 2)
    - Dwiggins, W. A., 1913-1955 (Box 2)
    - Eggert, Dorothy, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Farnum, Royal, 1937 (Box 2)
    - Farquar, Samuel, 1936-1937 (Box 2)
    - Faulkner, Richard, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Flagler, Harry Harkness, 1950 (Box 2)
    - French, Hannah, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Fulton, John, 1938, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Gandy, Lewis, 1937 (Box 2)
    - Garnett, Porter, 1931 (Box 2)
    - Gise, Margaret, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Gordon, Edmund, 1938 (Box 2)
    - Green, Charles, 1932-1933 (Box 2)
    - Green, James, undated (Box 2)
    - Griffith, C. H., 1932, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Griffith, Gillett, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Gud, Anton, 1935 (Box 2)
    - Hamilton, C. C., 1943 (Box 2)
    - Hammer, Victor, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Hardy, J. A., 1944 (Box 2)
    - Hart, Horace, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Hart, James, 1931 (Box 2)
    - Hawley, Alta, 1946 (Box 2)
    - Heintzemann, George, 1938 (Box 2)
    - Hicken, Edward, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Hofer, Philip, 1937, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Howe, Eric, 1948 (Box 2)
    - Hubbard, K. S., 1940 (Box 2)
    - Hugo, Harold, 1951, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Johnson, Mr. and Mrs. Foster, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Jorgenson, Arthur, 1935 (Box 2)
    - Kegley, M. C., 1938 (Box 2)
    - Kent, H. W., 1932-1941 (Box 2)
    - Kellog, Spencer, 1925 (Box 2)
    - Keynes, Quentin, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Kimball, LeRoy E., 1934, 1935 (Box 2)
    - Kimber, Sidney A., 1934 (Box 2)
    - Laughlin, Curtis, 1929 (Box 2)
    - LeFarge, M., 1938 (Box 2)
    - Leigh, Robert D., 1936 (Box 2)
    - Lehmann-Haupt, Hellmut, 1946 (Box 2)
    - Lerner, Max, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Long, Perry, 1946 (Box 2)
    - Loring, Augustus P., 1941-1943 (Box 2)
    - Loring, Rosamond, undated (Box 2)
    - Loveman, Amy, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Mackay, Mrs. A. F., 1924 (Box 2)
    - Mackay, Mary, 1938 (Box 2)
    - Macy, George, 1930-1944 (Box 2)
    - McClelland, John R., 1936 (Box 2)
    - McGuire, William, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Mechlin, Leila, 1934 (Box 2)
    - Miers, Earl Schenck, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Monison, Stanley, 1947 (Box 2)
    - Nash, John, 1943-1946 (Box 2)
    - Packard, George, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Phelps, Soule, 1959 (Box 2)
    - Phinney, J. W., 1932 (Box 2)
    - Reidy, Joseph, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Robinson, Stella, 1932 (Box 2)
    - Rogers, Bruce, 1905-1954 (Box 2)
    - Rudge, William, 1947 (Box 2)
    - Rudge, William, undated (Box 2)
    - Scudder, Townsend, undated (Box 3)
    - Simon, Oliver, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Sizer, Mr. And Mrs. Theodore, 1959 (Box 3)
    - Soule, Phelps, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Standard, Paul, 1931-1959 (Box 3)
    - Stevens, Edward, 1932-1933 (Box 3)
    - Stoddard, Charles, 1941 (Box 3)
    - Street, Julian, 1943 (Box 3)
    - Sturgis, Jerry M., 1932 (Box 3)
    - Taylor, Gehman, 1937 (Box 3)
    - Templetin, Richard H., 1945 (Box 3)
    - Thompson, Dan, 1933-1937 (Box 3)
    - Thomson, Edmund, 1940 (Box 3)
    - Tinker, Chauncey, 1924 (Box 3)
    - Tinker, Edward, 1933 (Box 3)
    - Treadway, Faith, undated (Box 3)
    - Tuttle, H. E., 1932 (Box 3)
    - Turabian, Kate L., 1947 (Box 3)
    - Twicenell, Katharine, undated (Box 3)
    - Updike, D. B., 1921-1948 (Box 3)
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison, 1940 (Box 3)
    - Virgin, Edward, 1916-1920 (Box 3)
    - Washburn, Gordon, 1933 (Box 3)
    - Watiles, G. (Box 3)
    - Weitenkampf, Frank, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Wells, James, 1929 (Box 3)
    - Wescott, Paul, undated (Box 3)
    - Weston, Amos, 1937 (Box 3)
    - Whiting, Fred, 1909-1951 (Box 3)
    - Whiting, Margaret, undated (Box 3)
    - Wilberforce, Robert, 1941 (Box 3)
    - Wight, R. A., 1939 (Box 3)
    - Withington, Robert, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Wormser, Dick, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Wroth, Lawrence, 1940, 1948 (Box 3)
    - Responses to 1951 Card (Box 3)
    - Responses to 1956 Card (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 3)
  - Correspondence of Margaret Rollins (Mrs. Carl Rollins)
    - Dye, Eleanor, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Eckman, James, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Hazen, Allen, 1955, 1956 (Box 4)
    - Hitchings, Sinclair, 1963 (Box 4)
    - McGuire, William, 1960 (Box 4)
    - Rettberg, William, 1961 (Box 4)
    - Sauerlander, W., 1960 (Box 4)
    - Thompson, Violet, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Third-Party Correspondence
    - Beakler, H. to George Day, 1921 (Box 4)
    - Bingham, William to Theodore Sizer, 1932 (Box 4)
    - Cary, Melbert to Will Ransom, 1928 (Box 4)
    - Delaherche, Auguste to J. Fosdick, undated (Box 4)
    - Freeman, Anna to Fred Whiting, 1931 (Box 4)
    - Jones, George to Bruce Rogers, 1922 (Box 4)
    - Leffingwell, R. C. to James Babb, 1955 (Box 4)
    - Rogers to Altschul, 1928 (Box 4)
    - Riterschun, H. to Edward Virgin (Box 4)
- Writings by and about Carl Rollins, 1930-1983; Series II
  - Writings by Rollins (Box 5)
  - Writings about Rollins, 1930-1983, undated (Box 6)
  - "Address at a Dinner to Mark the Seventy-Fifth Birthday of Carl Purington Rollins", 1965 (Box 6)
  - Talk by Greer Allen about Rollins, [198?] (Box 6)
  - Writings about Rollins, undated (Box 52)
    General note
    (Oversize +)
- Work and projects of Carl Rollins, 1900-1963; Series III
  - Bibliographic list of jobs done by Rollins (Box 7)
  - Bibliographic Press at Yale, 1930 (Box 7)
  - Bibliographic Press at Yale, 1934 (Box 7)
  - Bibliographic Press at Yale, 1927-1953 (Box 48)
    (Oversize)
  - Bibliographic Press at Yale, undated (Box 52)
  - Branford College Press at Yale, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Heintzemann Press, 1900-1901 (Box 7)
  - Heintzemann Press, 1902-1903 (Box 7)
  - Heintzemann Press, 1909-1941 (Box 7)
  - Heintzemann Press, undated (Box 7)
  - Jonathan Edwards Press at Yale, 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - Jonathan Edwards Press at Yale, 1939-1944 (Box 7)
  - Jonathan Edwards Press at Yale, undated (Box 7)
  - Montague Press, 1906-1926 (Box 7)
  - Montague Press, undated (Box 7)
  - Montague Press, 1916, 1917 (Box 48)
  - Montague Press, undated (Box 48)
  - Montague Press, undated (Box 52)
  - Sign of the Chorobates, 1920-1940 (Box 8)
  - Sign of the Chorobates, undated (Box 8)
  - Sign of the Chorobates, undated (Box 48)
  - Sign of the Chorobates, 1938 (Box 50)
  - Snowbound (J. G. Whittier) (Box 48)
  - Silliman College Press at Yale, 1942 (Box 8)
  - Timothy Dwight Press at Yale, 1938 (Box 8)
  - Timothy Dwight Press at Yale (Box 47)
  - Timothy Dwight Press at Yale, undated (Box 50)
  - Yale University Press, undated (Box 8)
  - Yale University Press, 1919-1929 (Box 8)
  - Yale University Press, 1930-1940 (Box 8)
  - Yale University Press, 1941-1946 (Box 9)
  - Yale University Press, 1947-1956 (Box 9)
  - Yale University Press, 1957-1963 (Box 9)
  - Yale University Press Letterheads (Box 9)
  - Yale University Press, undated (Box 9)
  - Yale University Press, 1956 (Box 48)
  - Yale University Press, 1926-1942 (Box 50)
  - Yale University Press, 1922-1956 (Box 53)
  - Yale University Press, 1922-1956 (Box 54)
  - Dust Jackets – YUP (Box 10)
  - Bookplates (Box 10)
  - Letterheads (Box 11)
  - Wine Labels (Box 11)
  - Tablets designed by CPR, undated (Box 11)
  - Aging Successfully by Lawton (*corr.: Scott, Catherine and CPR), undated (Box 11)
  - Alcuin by Charles Brockden Brown, undated (Box 11)
  - Requests for Alcuin by Charles Brockden Brown, undated (Box 11)
  - Jobs, American Magazine of Art, 1931 (Box 11)
  - Choate, undated (Box 11)
  - Eastern Corporation, undated (Box 11)
  - Hancock Shaker Village, 1960-1963 (Box 11)
  - Happy Life, A (*P. J. Conkwright), undated (Box 11)
  - International Library of Peru, undated (Box 11)
  - Job for Japan Paper Company (*George Nelson, CPR), undated (Box 11)
  - Miss Porter's School (*Ward Johnson), undated (Box 11)
  - Pomfret School-Diploma-CPR Designs, 1942 (Box 11)
  - Prospect Hill School, undated (Box 11)
  - Recording for the Blind, Inc., 1963 (Box 11)
  - Red Badge of Courage (*George Macy and CPR), undated (Box 11)
  - Ticonderoga Pulp, undated (Box 11)
  - Walpole, Correspondence, undated (Box 11)
  - Walpole Drafts, undated (Box 11)
  - Walpole Drafts, undated (Box 11)
  - What Cheer (*Tim Coward), undated (Box 12)
  - Jobs-Misc. (undated) 12 Misc. Projects (Box 12)
  - Misc. Projects (Box 54)
  - Misc. Projects (Box Bsd)
- Awards, Honors, and Events, 1933-1963; Series IV
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts dinner, undated (Box 13)
  - Birthday, 75th, minutes (Box 13)
  - Birthday, 75th, cards and greetings (Box 13)
  - Birthday, 75th, correspondence (Box 13)
  - Birthday, 80th, correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Beinecke presentation, 1963 (Box 13)
  - Dartmouth exhibition, 1947 (Box 13)
  - Dyke Mill party, 1959 (Box 13)
  - Graphic Arts Institute dinner (Box 13)
  - Limited Editions Club (Box 66)
  - Membership certificates (Box 13)
  - Montague party, 1954 (Box 13)
  - New Haven Lawn Club dinner, 1955 (Box 13)
  - Pratt Institute exhibit, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Rollins Printing Office Fund, undated (Box 13)
  - Rounce and Coffin Club dinner, 1948 (Box 13)
  - Society of Printers exhibit, 1950 (Box 13)
  - Yale University Library donation (Box 13)
  - Yale University Press Master Printer, 1949 (Box 50)
- Book Clubs and Bibliophile Groups, 1902-1965; Series V
  - Acorn Club, 1902-1946 (Box 14)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts, The, 1965 (Box 14)
  - Bacchus Club, undated (Box 14)
  - Bacchus Club, undated (Box 48)
  - Park Bennet Galleries, Inc., 1947 (Box 14)
  - Book Club of California, 1935-1939 (Box 14)
  - Bookbuilders (Boston), 1942-1947 (Box 14)
  - Caxton Club, 1939 (Box 14)
  - Club of Odd Volumes, 1915-1956 (Box 14)
  - Colonial Society of Massachusetts (Box 14)
  - Columbiad Club, 1930-1994 (Box 14)
  - Columbiad Club (Box 14)
  - Columbiad Club, minutes, 1934-1940 (Box 14)
  - Columbiad Club, minutes, 1941-1954 (Box 14)
  - Columbiad Club, 1973 (Box 50)
  - Double Crown Club, 1947-1959 (Box 15)
  - Goodspeed's Bookshop, 1954-1960 (Box 15)
  - Grolier Club, 1901-1925 (Box 16)
  - Grolier Club, 1939-1941 (Box 16)
  - Grolier Club, 1942-1945 (Box 16)
  - Grolier Club, 1946-1947 (Box 16)
  - Grolier Club, 1948-1959 (Box 17)
  - Grolier Club, undated (Box 17)
  - Grolier Club, 1955 (Box 50)
  - Limited Editions Club, 1929-1955 (Box 18)
  - Limited Editions Club, 1954 (Box 48)
  - LXIVmos, 1928, 1929 (Box 19)
  - Myopia Hunt Club, 1897 (Box 19)
  - Publishers Weekly, 1953 (Box 19)
  - Rounce and Coffin Club, 1939-1952 (Box 19)
  - Roxburghe Club, 1952 (Box 48)
  - Saturday Review of Literature, The, 1924-1934, 1949 (Box 55)
  - San Francisco Printer, 1930 (Box 19)
  - Society of Printers, 1906-1956 (Box 19)
  - Typophiles, 1938-1958 (Box 19)
  - Typophiles, undated (Box 48)
  - Walpole Society, 1948 (Box 19)
  - William Morris Society, 1957-1960 (Box 19)
  - Zamorano Club, 1952-1956 (Box 20)
  - Zamorano Club, 1957, 1958 (Box 20)
  - Zamorano Club, 1959-1961 (Box 20)
  - Zamorano Club, undated (Box 20)
  - Zamorano Club, undated (Box 48)
- Presses, 1902-1963; Series VI
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains ephemeral publications, prospecti, broadsides, etc., collected by Rollins from various presses.
  - Akerman Standard Press, 1947 (Box 21)
  - Alcuin Press, undated (Box 21)
  - Alpress Press, 1935 (Box 21)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1931 (Box 21)
  - Angel Alley Press, 1929 (Box 21)
  - Anthoensen Press, 1947 (Box 21)
  - Anvil Press, undated (Box 21)
  - Archetype Press, 1937-1939 (Box 21)
  - Archetype Press, undated (Box 57)
  - Aries Press, 1926 (Box 21)
  - Atar Press, 1924 (Box 21)
  - Banyan Press, undated (Box 21)
  - Between Hours Press, 1952 (Box 21)
  - Black Cat Press, 1934-1937 (Box 21)
  - Black Sun Press, 1929 (Box 21)
  - Blue Ox Press, undated (Box 21)
  - Bodoni Press, 1923 (Box 21)
  - Bohme & Blinkmann, 1938 (Box 21)
  - Bookman Press, 1933-1938 (Box 21)
  - Bowling Green Press, undated (Box 21)
  - Brad Stephens and Co., 1921 (Box 21)
  - Bremer Press, undated (Box 21)
  - Bremer Press, 1924-1928 (Box 48)
  - Brookdale Press (Box 21)
  - Brothers of the Book, 1912 (Box 21)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1952-1959 (Box 22)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1924 (Box 48)
  - Cantina Press, 1939 (Box 22)
  - Castle Press, The, 1954 (Box 22)
  - Chatto & Windus (Box 22)
  - Clarendon Press, 1938 (Box 50)
  - Cole-Holmquist Press, The, 1929 (Box 48)
  - Colish, A., 1959 (Box 50)
  - Colt Press, 1939-1941 (Box 22)
  - Condé Nast Press, 1934 (Box 22)
  - Corydon Press, 1945 (Box 22)
  - Cosmos Press, 1928 (Box 22)
  - Countryman Press, 1941 (Box 22)
  - Cranach Press (Box 22)
  - Cranbrook Press (Box 22)
  - Cresset Press, 1928-1930 (Box 22)
  - Cresset Press, 1927 (Box 50)
  - Cummington Press, 1944-1955 (Box 22)
  - Currier Press, 1922 (Box 22)
  - Curwen Press, 1930 (Box 22)
  - Cygnet Press, 1929 (Box 22)
  - Devinne Press, 1904-1927 (Box 22)
  - Dogwood Press, 1931 (Box 22)
  - Domesday Press, 1937 (Box 22)
  - R. R. Donnelley and Sons Co., 1953 (Box 22)
  - Eaglebrook Press, 1946 (Box 23)
  - Eddy Press (Box 48)
  - Elm Tree Press, 1911-1942 (Box 23)
  - Elston Press, 1902 (Box 23)
  - E. L. Hildreth & Co. (Box 23)
  - Equinox Press, The, 1947 (Box 57)
  - Essex House Press (Box 23)
  - Eucalyptus Press, 1937,1939 (Box 23)
  - Eugrammia Press (Box 48)
  - Fanfare Press (Box 23)
  - Fanfrolico Press, 1929 (Box 23)
  - Fanfrolico Press (Box 48)
  - Fieldston School Press, 1935 (Box 23)
  - Flame Press, 1930 (Box 23)
  - Fleuron, Ltd., The, 1926,1927 (Box 23)
  - Galahad Press (Box 24)
  - Gentry Press (Box 24)
  - Golden Cockerel Press, 1925-1937 (Box 24)
  - Golden Cockerel Press, 1934 (Box 48)
  - Golden Hind Press, 1942 (Box 24)
  - Golden Hind Press, undated (Box 50)
  - Grabhorn Press, 1930 (Box 24)
  - Grayhound Press, 1931 (Box 24)
  - Greenwich Press (Box 24)
  - Greenwood Press, 1944 (Box 24)
  - Gregnog Press, 1927 (Box 24)
  - Gryphon Press (Box 24)
  - Hadham Press, undated (Box 24)
  - Halycon Press, 1930 (Box 24)
  - Harbor Press, 1926-1939 (Box 24)
  - Harrison of Paris, 1932 (Box 24)
  - Harvard V.P., 1963 (Box 24)
  - Harvest Press, undated (Box 24)
  - Hawthorn House, 1931-1946 (Box 24)
  - Heintzemann Press, 1903 (Box 24)
  - Helen Gentry Press, 1934 (Box 24)
  - Heritage Press, 1936 (Box 24)
  - Hobby House Press, 1937-1945 (Box 24)
  - Hours Press, 1929 (Box 24)
  - Imprimerie Nationale, 1923 (Box 25)
  - John Crown Companionship, 1941 (Box 25)
  - Jumbo Press, 1937,1938 (Box 25)
  - Knopf, undated (Box 25)
  - La Belle Sauvage Press (Box 25)
  - Latin Press, 1935,1936 (Box 25)
  - Lakeside Press, 1944,1948 (Box 25)
  - Lakeside Press, undated (Box 48)
  - Lincoln and Smith Press, 1956 (Box 25)
  - Mainzer Presse, 1928 (Box 26)
  - Mallette Dean, undated (Box 26)
  - Marchbanks Press, 1915-1935 (Box 26)
  - Meriden Gravure, 1935 (Box 27)
  - Meriden Gravure, 1951 (Box 48)
  - Merrymount Press, 1902-1941 (Box 27)
  - Monadnock Press, undated (Box 27)
  - Morland Press, undated (Box 48)
  - Nonesuch Press, 1923-1925 (Box 28)
  - Offhand Press, 1958-1960 (Box 28)
  - Old Farms Press, 1931-1933 (Box 28)
  - Old Farms Press, undated (Box 50)
  - Oswald Press, 1916 (Box 28)
  - Oxford University Press, 1944 (Box 28)
  - Parnassus Press, undated (Box 29)
  - Pear Tree Press, 1934,1938 (Box 29)
  - Pegasus Press, undated (Box 29)
  - Pelican Press, 1921,1922 (Box 29)
  - Penguin Books Ltd, 1951 (Box 29)
  - Periwinkle Press, 1939 (Box 29)
  - Peter Pauper Press, 1936,1942 (Box 29)
  - Pickering Press, 1953 (Box 29)
  - Pine Bough Press, 1946 (Box 50)
  - Plantin Press, 1935 (Box 29)
  - Powgen Press, undated (Box 29)
  - Prairie Press, 1936 (Box 29)
  - Press in Rowayton, 1947 (Box 29)
  - Press of Norman T. A. Munder, undated (Box 29)
  - Press of the Blue Dolphin, undated (Box 29)
  - Press of the Brown Pan (Pudgy Bear Press), undated (Box 50)
  - Press of the Booklet, The, 1935 (Box 29)
  - Press of the Woolly Whale, undated (Box 48)
  - Press of the Woolly Whale, undated (Box 54)
  - Princeton University Press, 1922 (Box 29)
  - Prospect Press, undated (Box 29)
  - Profile Press, 1930-1931 (Box 29)